# ZACHARIAH SHAREK

sharek@gmail.com • (919) 757-4569

Entrepreneurial Carnegie Mellon Tepper Ph.D. that applies market research startup experience and an academic background in management and strategy to lead teams making data driven decisions. Focused on designing solutions by understanding organizational and consumer needs combined with strong data analysis skills.

## Experience

BBC Worldwide

Pittsburgh, PA

Executive Director of Apturis

2/2016-current

- Recruited by senior leadership at the BBC to lead a market research initiative focusing on improving global marketing strategy and decision-making
- Developed multiple data products using novel data sources, enabling real-time global comparison of the BBC's marketing efforts
- **Rhiza**, A Draper Triangle funded marketing analytics startup Senior Vice President of Product Strategy

Pittsburgh, PA 11/2014–1/2016

- Led a team of 18 product managers, developers and data scientists in creating products for data-driven marketing analysis for media ad sales clients; Resulted in 24 new customers and 200% increase in monthly recurring revenue
- Directed business development of partnerships with top providers of syndicated marketing data, including Nielsen, Rentrak, Experian and Polk
- Consulted with media clients to optimize ad sales revenue and consumer research; Increased success of ad sales pitches by 75%
- **CivicScience**, A NPD Group funded big data consumer insights startup *Director of Strategy & Innovation*

**Pittsburgh, PA** 3/2013–10/2014

- Led the company's consumer insights consulting team; Tripled consulting revenue within one year
- Developed marketing strategy and ROI analytic models for healthcare clients using over 500 million insurance claims; Increased advertising ROI by over 50%
- Created data products identifying persuadable consumers; Resulted in acquiring over 30 consumer goods clients, including General Mills, T-Mobile and Samsung
- Tepper School of Business, Carnegie Mellon University Researcher & Instructor

Pittsburgh, PA 7/2006–5/2012

- Research focus on strategy & management, especially judgment & decision-making
- Awarded \$223,000 National Science Foundation grant on behavioral biases in decisionmaking resulting in four papers & seven conference presentations
- Instructor for classes on management, decision-making and negotiations with teaching evaluations in top 10% of university

## Zachariah Sharek

#### Experience continued

## • Harvard Business School, Harvard University

Boston, MA

Research Associate

1/2006-7/2006

- Created models of media consumption from analysis of multi-terabyte datasets; including the largest ever dataset HBS had used for research
- Designed economic experiments investigating behavioral game theory, the results were used in three academic papers
- Managed experimental economic lab; Supervised three research assistants; Developed and administered over 25 experiments

• Accenture Consultant Charlotte, NC 8/2003–7/2005

- Led an international team of 15 programmers & testers in successfully stress-testing an online-banking website with over \$300 billion of deposits
- Designed and lead implementation of mortgage securitization and re-underwriting software that processed up to \$10 billion of mortgages daily for a financial startup
- Created a statistical model determining which mortgages to re-underwrite; Resulted in 33% increase in mortgage securities processing speed

#### **EDUCATION**

## • Tepper School of Business, Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

Ph.D., Organizational Behavior & Theory (Strategy & Management)

8/2006-5/2012

Expertise: strategy, judgment & decision-making, behavioral economics, negotiations

## • University of North Carolina

Chapel Hill, NC

MS, Information Science

8/2000-12/2002

BA, Economics & Philosophy

8/1996-12/1999

- Played Division 1 rugby; Selected to North Carolina All-Star team
- Developer on TeraScale Retrieval, a National Science Foundation funded project
- Transfered from Duke University after freshman year

## Additional Information

**Nonprofit Work:** Director Emeritus of the Association for the Coral Environment, Advisor to the Executive Director of the Bahamas Reef Environment Education Fund (BREEF)

**Activities:** Statistical analysis for breast cancer research, competitive kettlebell lifting & instruction, designing & playing board games